Truong Nguyen

tristannguyen03@gmail.com (714) 345 1841 Anaheim, CA 92801

OBJECTIVE OVERVIEW

With five years of experience in computer networks as a system administrator, I am not only strong at programming, monitoring the network efficiency and planning the appropriate system needs of a company but also soft skills, including commercial awareness, leadership and teamwork skill. I am seeking an internship, part-time or full-time jobs.

EDUCATION

California State University, Fullerton

Expected Nov 2020

 Master of Science in Computer Science Concentration in Computer Networks & Security

Hong Bang International University

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam 2010-2014

• B.S. Certificate in Information Technology

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Research volunteering.

Fullerton, California 2017-2018

Department of Computer Science, California State University, Fullerton

- I am doing research about security issues in IoT/Smart Grid with a special focus on BlockChain.
- Report to Dr. Wenlin Han, who is a tenure-track assistant professor in the Department of Computer Science.

IT Systems Administrator

Hoa Sao Group

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam 2013-2015

- Planned and executed of tasks related to the evaluation of Active Directory based initiatives, (Upgraded Versions, Third-Party Solutions, and Integration with additional Enterprise Systems).
- Maintained and administered Active Directory Servers, including daily monitoring, troubleshooting and performance analysis.
- Worked with business users to document and analyze workflows that will be automated in Active Directory.
- Worked with business users to address requirements, usability, accessibility, security and change requests to ensure Active Directory functionality.
- Installed and deployed Active Directory services, perform system upgrades and patching, make recommendations for system improvements, and ensure the integrity of the Active Directory in accordance industry best practices.
- Maintained servers that provide standard services such as DNS, DHCP, IIS, FTP and SFTP services.
- Windows Server support, Active Directory and Exchange, Windows server 2003 2012.
- Implemented and maintain SAN from various vendors.
- Managed resource allocation on ESXi host.
- Reviewed, improve, and manage the server, network storage, and workstation backup strategy.
- Configured services on various VMs to support customer products.
- Built servers/virtual machines and configure to specifications needed for application deployment.
- Provided Infrastructure services in all areas needed: storage networking, Operating System, network security, directory services, server virtualization using system backup and restore, system and network monitoring, application installation and configuration.

- Coordinated on installation and maintenance needs for applications with the IT team.
- Configured, test, and maintain LAN equipment and services, including switches, routers, firewalls, and VPN.
- VOIP Phone Administration (including SIP lines/router, physical equipment).

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Service Desk Support

Lotte Vietnam (LOTTE Data Communication Company)

Korea 2010-2013

- Diagnosed and troubleshoots end-user desktop application issues and provides appropriate solution.
- Supported end-users in their use of applications such as Microsoft Office, CRM, VPN and MDM (mobile device management).
- Communicated with customers at all levels of technical and non-technical skills sets.
- Provided support for PCs, laptops, printers, cell phones, and tablets etc.
- Developed, documented, and implemented standard operating procedures and customer service guidelines relating to remote IT support.
- Complied with regulatory laws, employee handbook, department policy and procedures, safety codes etc.
- Ensured that operation of equipment, tools and materials are handled in a safe manner.
- Monitored various server infrastructure components and logs.
- Assisted in the development, maintenance and distribution of IT policies and procedures.
- Complied with regulatory laws, employee handbook, department policy and procedures, safety codes etc
- Installed, test and configure new workstations, peripheral equipment and software.
- Maintained inventory of all equipment, software and software licenses.
- Assigned users and computers to proper groups in Active Directory.

SKILLS

- CCNA Routing & Switching
- MCSA + MCTS 2008 & 2012 + MESSAGING + SECURITY
- MCSE + MCITP-EA
- Microsoft Forefront Threat Management Gateway
- PC TROUBLESHOOTING
- Html and Javascript
- Programming Arduino with C
- C/C++.
- Prolog, CLIPS programming language.
- Configuring and Managing Microsoft SharePoint 2010
- Linux Systems Administration
- vCenter & VMware ESXi 3 6.0
- Administering and supporting VMWare environments.
- Languages: English and Vietnamese